SHRI HANUMANA PUJA APRIL 23, 1989
哈奴曼崇拜 1989年4月23日
MARGATE, KENT, ENGLAND
英国马盖特
It is such a joy today
今天极之喜乐
and the whole atmosphere seems to be bubbling with it,
整个气氛好像都充满这份喜乐
as if the angels are singing.
就如天使在歌唱
And the speciality of Hanumana was that He was an angel.
哈奴曼特别在祂是天使
Angels are born like angels. They are angels
天使就如天使般出生 他们是天使
and they are not human beings.
不是人类
They're born with the angelic qualities.
带着天使的品质出生
But now you all have become angels from the human beings.
现在 你们都已从人类变成天使
It's a very great achievement of Sahaja Yoga.
这是霎哈嘉瑜伽很了不起的成就
The qualities that are born with the angels
天使出生时的品质
are seen from their very childhood.
在他们孩童时就已能看到
Firstly, they are not afraid of untruth, falsehood.
首先 他们不畏惧不真实 虚假
They're not worried as to what people will say to them,
他们不会担忧人们怎么说他们
or what they will lose in life.
或他们生命中会失去什么
To them truth is their life, they breathe truth
对他们而言 真理就是他们的生命 他们呼吸真理
and nothing else matters with them.
没有什么可以干扰他们
This is the first great quality of an angel.
这是天使首要的伟大品质
They will go to any extent to establish truth, to protect,
他们会极力建立真理 保护真理
and to protect the people who are in truth.
并且保护真理之人
It's such a wide range of these angels, all over.
这些天使们广泛的遍布四周
So in the left side we have ganas,
在左边 我们有伽蓝仙众(ganas)
on the right side we have angels. And translated in
右边则有天使
means they are the ambassadors of God.
意思是他们是诸神的大使
So now you are the same, you are all angels now.
你们现在也一样 全都是天使
Only thing, you are not aware that you are angels,
唯一的分别是你不知道自己是天使
while they were aware from their childhood.
而他们却在孩童时已经知道
If you know that you are angels,
若你知道自己是天使
all your qualities will start shining through
你的所有品质会开始闪耀
and you'll be amazed that
你会很惊讶
the quality of standing by the truth
对你而言 不惜一切
at any cost is so easily managed for you,
坚持真理是那么容易
because you have been given the right,
因为你已获授权力
you have been given the special blessings, the special protection
已赐予你特别的福佑 你特别受
from the Divine that
上天的保护
if you stand for the right and if you stand
若你支持正确的事情
for the righteous and if you stand for the truth,
支持正义 支持真理
all kinds of help to protect you will be given.
就会得到一切的帮助 一切的保护
Angels are aware of this, they're sure of it, they are certain,
天使知道会这样 他们亦肯定会这样 他们肯定
there's a certainty about it. But you are not.
很肯定会这样 但你却不肯定
You still sometimes think, “May be, may not be.”
你有时仍会想 或许不会这样
Same style goes on. But believe Me, you are angels.
这种想法持续 相信我 你们是天使
You have all the powers, and what rights you have!
你们拥有所有力量 你有什么权力
Human beings cannot get over you,
人类不能超越你
that’s the speciality of angels, not of saints.
这是天使特别之处 不是圣人
Saint could be maneuvered.
圣人会受人摆布
They could be tortured, they could be troubled.
受人折磨 有人找他们麻烦
Incarnations may do the same. Incarnations accept it,
降世神祇 或许也一样 降世神祇会接受这些摆布折磨
they want to have all these penances done to them
他们想行这样的苦行
so that they create an event in their life
那么他们就能在生命中创造事件
to express themselves in a more dynamic way. If there was no Ravana,
以更有活力的方式来表达自己 若没有拉伐那(Ravana)
there would have been no Ramayana;
就没有《罗摩衍那》(Ramayana)
if there was no Kamsa, there would have been no Krishna.
若没有金沙 就没有克里希纳
So the incarnations take upon themselves the problems and
所以降世神祇担起问题
also the fight with the evil.
与邪恶作战
So it looks sometimes that we feel that they suffer, but they don’t.
所以有时表面看来他们在受苦 实际上他们并没有受苦
But angels are a special category,
天使是属于特别的类别
they don’t take up any problems upon themselves, they just solve them.
他们不会担起任何问题 他们只会解决问题
If there’s a problem, it’s the angels who solve,
若有问题 天使就来解决
for the saints as well as for the incarnations.
既为圣人亦为降世神祇解决问题
And they have to be told sometimes that “Don’t jump in just now,
有人有时会告诉他们 现在不要跳进来
we are working out on the stage now, You will jump when we’ll ask you.”
我们在台上正在解决问题 我们要求你们时 你们才跳进来吧
They're ready standing at the door just to jump in.
他们站在门前 准备就绪
So anxious!
很渴望想跳进来
And they are fixed quantities;
他们有固定的数量
you can rely on them completely.
你能完全依赖他们
For example, Shri Hanumana, as you know Him as an angel,
就以哈奴曼为例 你们也知道他作为天使
has great capacities, great powers,
有很大的能耐 很大的力量
and it is His right to use them
这是他的权利去运用这些力量
and He is very aware of it.
他亦完全知道自己的力量
He does everything very amusingly, uses His powers very amusingly.
他很有趣的做一切 很有趣的运用他的力量
Like He burnt the whole of Lanka and He was laughing at it.
就像他烧毁整个兰卡城(Lanka) 还取笑它
Then He extended His tail
接着他伸展他的尾巴
and put it round the necks of many rakshasas
用尾巴缠着很多恶魔的颈
and He was just playing with them and then flew in the air, and
他只是玩弄他们 再飞上天空
they all were dangling in the air.
恶魔全都悬吊在天空里
So it’s a playfulness of the angels also
这是天使开的玩笑
because they're so confident,
因为他们都很有自信
they're absolutely aware,
完全知道
absolutely identified with their personality,
完全认同于他们的个性
with their powers, with themselves.
他们的力量 也完全认同于自己
Here the Sahaja Yogis sometimes don’t understand
在这里 霎哈嘉瑜伽士有时不明白
that I have made you into angels.
我已经创造你们成为天使
I’ve not made you into saints, but angels,
我不是创造你们成为圣人 而是天使
and you are always protected.
你们常常受到保护
I can only make angels, I can’t make saints.
我只能制造天使 不能制造圣人
Saints are made by their own effort.
圣人是他们自己的努力而成
The effortlessness doing is like Ganesha,
不用花力气 就如格涅沙
like Karttikeya, like Hanumana.
如卡提凯亚 如哈奴曼
The same way you are all made, with the same style.
同样你们全都是同一模式风格被创造出来
So try to understand
因此你们要尝试明白
that what I say about you is the truth.
我说关于你的都是真理
All kinds of conditionings work
虽然你们是圣人
even through you people though you are saints
却仍受各种制约限制
and you don’t know how to spread your wings.
仍不懂怎样伸展你的翼
Still, sometimes I feel that
仍然 有时 我感到他们
the rebirth has taken place
已经重生
and they have all become like angels with wings,
全都变成有翼的天使
but as little birds, they still have to learn how to fly.
但作为小鸟 他们仍要学习怎样飞
But you must gain your confidence
你要透过在霎哈嘉瑜伽的经验
by your experiences which you have in Sahaja Yoga.
取得信心
As you were singing yesterday, miracles, every day miracles around you.
就如你们昨天唱的歌曲 每一天都有奇迹 奇迹围绕着你
These are done by the angels
这些奇迹都是天使创造的
and they try to convince you that “You are one of us,
他们想说服你 你们是我们的一份子
just join our company.”
只要加入我们
So we have so many angels now sitting here,
我们有那么多天使现在坐在这里
and why should not we think of transforming this world?
为何我们不想想转化这个世界
And there’s one more thing
你们比天使拥有
that you have other than the angels,
多一种东西
because angels do not raise the Kundalini,
因为天使不提升灵量
they cannot, they're not bothered about it.
他们不能 亦不在意
They are there to kill, to burn, to suppress,
他们来只为杀戮 烧毁 镇压
to remove all the evil people around you.
移除围绕你们身边邪恶的人
But they cannot transform, angels cannot transform.
他们不能转化 天使不能转化人
So you have a greater right than they have in the realm of God,
所以在神的国度 你比他们有更大的权力
that you can raise the Kundalini of people
就是你能提升人的灵量
and you can give Realization.
能给人自觉
But human conditionings are still sticking on.
但人类的制约仍黏贴着你
For example, I wore a ring the other day,
例如 有天我戴上戒指
and then My daughter starting teasing Me that
我的女儿嘲笑我
“Now you must only show this finger all the time
现在你必定只会向人展示这只手指
to people so that they see Your ring.”
那么他们就能看到你的戒指
So in the mundane human life, whatever we have –
在俗世 不管我们拥有什么
possessions maybe, powers you see -
财产 或许权势
for example, somebody is a man with some position,
例如 某人处于某个地位
immediately you can make it out with his
你立即能从他的嘴脸
nose and lips, the way they are turned upward.
他颠倒事非的态度看出来
But the powers that you have in your possession,
你已经拥有力量
you’re afraid to manifest them and to talk about it, to use them.
你却害怕彰显它 谈论它 运用它
Imagine, with so many angels
试想像 有那么多天使
the whole of England should get Realization in no time,
整个英国应该很快的得到自觉
but we are still trying to learn what we are.
但我们仍在学习我们是谁
Hanumana had no problem
哈奴曼没有这个问题
because from His childhood He knew that He was an angel and
因为他自孩提开始就知道自己是天使
He has to do the job of an angel.
要做天使的工作
But because we were born as human beings and now we have become angels,
我们生而为人类 现在我们已经成为天使
we find it difficult to be dynamic like other angels that they were.
我们发现 像其他天使般 那么有活力是很困难的
Even your thought, collective thought,
即使你的思绪 集体的思绪
even your individual thought, is powerful,
甚至你的思绪 也是很有力量
and your attention is powerful.
你的注意力亦很有力量
Because of this fear, or maybe the conditionings as you can call it,
因为恐惧 或许是你称为的思想制约
or maybe the ego part which is still sticking onto you,
又或许是你仍黏贴着自我
you still hang around false things,
仍与虚假的事物混在一起
and that force, that dynamism is not expressed.
因此 这份力量 这份动力仍未彰显
We can blame anything, like we can blame lethargy to some country,
我们可以责怪任何事物 像我们可以责怪一些国家的倦怠
ego to some country, but now you have lost your countries completely,
一些国家的自我 但现在 你已经完全抛掉你的国家
now you have entered into the Kingdom of God.
你已经进入神的国度
You’re in a country which has no bounds, which has no limitations.
身处没有国界 没有限制的国家
And then, all these conditionings that are still lingering in you
那些仍然缠绕着你的制约
upset you or deter you from doing whatever is your job.
为此感到沮丧 也不应因为它而阻碍你做你要做的工作
Now imagine, Hanumana as Gabriel had to go
现在试想像作为右天使长加伯利的哈奴曼
and tell Maria that “There’s a Child which is the Incarnation.
他要告诉玛利亚 她会生下一位降世神祇
The Savior is going to be born to You.” She was a young virgin.
一位救赎者 她是年青的处女
To break such a news which was horrible compared to
以那时候的制约相比
the conditionings of those days.
要说出这个可怕的消息
He did it -
他说了
“I have to do it so I’ll do it;
我要告诉玛利亚 我对她说了
if that’s the order, I’ll do it” -
若这是命令 我就照做
because He knew that the carrying out of the order
因为他知道执行命令是
is His nature, is built within Him
他的本质 这种本质已建构在他之内
and He’snot going to doubt it.
他对此毫无怀疑
He’s not going to wait, but just told and He does it.
他不会等候 立即就告诉玛利亚 他做了
So a great understanding has to be within us,
我们内在要有很了不起的理解
that we are growing within ourselves.
就是我们内在正在成长
But if we do not manifest,
但若我们不彰显
if we do not show our qualities,
不彰显我们的品质
and if we do not express it in our life,
不在我们的生命里
in our doing, in our object, in the meaning of our life,
言行里 目标里 我们生命的意义里 显现我们的品质
then Sahaja Yoga is not going to spread.
霎哈嘉瑜伽就不能传播
Nor is it going to help you much.
对你亦帮助不大
The kind of work you have to do has no problems with it.
你要做的工作没出什么问题
I have problems, not you.
是我出问题 不是你
You don’t have to face problems.
你不用面对问题
You go and talk to anyone, whatever you feel like.
你可以与任何你喜欢的人说 他们肯定会聆听你
They will jolly well have to listen to you, I should say.
即使他们不聆听你
But if they don’t, they can’t harm you.
也不能伤害你
They can’t do any harm to you.
他们对你不会有任何伤害
This is a very great protection you have, they cannot hinder your work.
这是你最大的保护 他们不能阻碍你的工作
Coming to Sahaja Yoga is not what we have gained,
来霎哈嘉瑜伽不在于我们已经得到什么
what we have got.
取得什么
See the people who say, “We've done so much for Sahaj Yoga
有些人说 我们为霎哈嘉瑜伽做了那么多工作
and what Sahaja Yoga has given us?”
霎哈嘉瑜伽给了我们什么
It has given you Self Realization.
霎哈嘉瑜伽给你自觉
It has given you the angel status.
给你天使的地位
I mean you try anything else,
我是说不管你怎样尝试
can you get the status of an angel? You cannot.
你能取得天使的地位吗
Sahaja Yoga has given you that status,
你不能 霎哈嘉瑜伽已经给你这个地位
so what more do you want?
你还想要什么
It was never possible before,
从来没有人拥有这个地位
believe Me, impossible situation.
相信我 这是不可能的境况
If it was possible in any way, then
若这有可能发生
Gyaneshwara would not have taken His samadhi at such a young age,
格尼殊哇就不会那么年青就进入三摩地
and Kabira would not have said, "Oh God, what am I to do?
而伽比尔亦不会说 噢 天啊 我该怎么办
This world is blind."
这个世界是盲的
So you have that subtle power within you
你内在拥有精微的力量
that you can work out on people’s Kundalini without even
你甚至在别人不知情下
they knowing about it.
提升他们的灵量
But in meditation when you sit down,
当你坐下入静
you must admit to yourself, “I’m an angel,
你必须承认 我是天使
and as being an angel,
作为天使
I have no attachments with anything else but with God’s work.”
除了神的工作 我什么也不依恋执着
Attachments are so many still in Sahaja Yoga I’ve seen people have,
有太多依恋执着 我在霎哈嘉瑜伽仍看到人有执着
like attachments to, now because they're married,
就如执着于 因为他们已婚
so they have attached to wives,
因此依恋着妻子
and so many have fallen out because of their wives attachments.
因为依恋着妻子 很多人已经离去
Then they have attachments to their children,
接着他们依恋他们的孩子
and so many will fall out if they have attachments to their children.
因此很多人离去 若你依恋着自己的孩子
As I told you yesterday
就如我昨天告诉你
that all the children of the world
这个世界所有霎哈嘉瑜伽士的孩子
who are Sahaja Yogis are your children.
都是你的孩子
You're the parents of all the children;
你是所有孩子的父母
it’s not that if your child is sleeping you cover that child.
不是说若你的孩子睡着了 你为他盖被子
No, you cover all the children.
不是 你为所有孩子盖被子
You have to look after all the children which are lying down.
你要照顾所有躺下的孩子
Can you think of Hanumana, if He was here
你想想哈奴曼 若他在这里
and when the children were sleeping It would just
当孩子睡了 他会只为
cover the body of one child?
一个孩子盖被子吗
Because He’s a universal being.
因为他是宇宙存在体
So every child has to be loved the same way, cared for by you.
你要爱每个孩子 照顾每个孩子
Then there are other attachments like possessions, positions, jobs.
其他依恋执着像财产 地位 工作
I have none so I don’t know what others are,
我没有任何一种 所以我不知道其他人是怎么样
except for when I see you
除了当我看到你们
so much lovingly coming to the station,
充满爱的来到车站
then the whole heart becomes like an ocean, I think, and just
我整颗心变得像海洋
starts like a big swell of a tide, like that and I see that.
像一个大浪涌来 像这样 我看到这个浪
And then when I have to leave you, again it recedes back like a sea
当我要离开你们 它就像海洋退去
which is now receding.
现在它正在退去
It’s something like, you see the moon
就像这样 你要明白
and the sea starts reacting to the beauty of the moon,
月亮和海洋对月亮的漂亮作出反应
the joy of the moon, the love of the moon.
月亮的喜乐 月亮的爱
Then I see the love, the love that is you see in a nest
接着我看到爱 那份在鸟巢里
where a bird is feeding its young ones.
鸟儿喂食幼鸟的爱
And you see this love in the sky,
你看到这份爱在天空里
then you see this love in your heart,
再看到这份爱在你心中
and only thing that you can describe is the feeling
唯一你能描述的是你内在有份如
of tremendous ocean of joy within you, just flowing out.
巨大海洋喜乐的感觉 只在流出
The attachments do not give you capacity to enjoy that ocean.
依恋执着不能给你享受海的能耐
If you are standing on the shore,
若你站在海岸
how will you enjoy the ocean? You have to jump into it.
怎能享受海 你要跳进海里
But you’ve got your anchorage onto different things, so you can’t jump in.
你却把锚停泊在不同事物上 因此你没法跳进海里
And you are so safe.
你是那么安全
You know how to swim, you know how to kill a shark,
你懂游泳 懂怎样杀掉鲨鱼
even one sight of yours is sufficient.
即使只看牠一眼已经足够
But because you're not aware, it is not acting.
但因为你仍未知道 它仍未活跃
Absolutely this is the case.
绝对是这种情况
I've seen people
我曾见过有人
who get small positions in life and they start boasting about it,
得到小小的位置 就开始吹嘘
“I met this-and-this man, I met
我遇过这个那个人
that-and-that man, and this happened and that happened.”
遇过这个那个人 这种事情发生 那种事情发生
You feel like laughing at the person I mean.
你对这个人只感到可笑
But you have met Sahaja Yoga,
你已经遇见霎哈嘉瑜伽
by which you have grown, you have been nourished,
藉此你已经成长 已经得到滋润
you have become so great.
已经变得了不起
With all this we have to follow the line of Hanumana.
藉此我们要跟随哈奴曼的路线
He thought the sun is very egoistical,
他认为太阳很自我中心
trying to burn people. Sometimes there's too much heat,
想烧伤人 有时有太多热力
and the sun worshippers also are egoistical.
太阳的敬拜者也太过自我
They have so much ego in them.
他们有太多自我
Any word if you say wrong in their language,
若你以他们的语言
or in their customs, say you hold
或他们的习俗说错任何话
the fork in the wrong hand – finished!
例如你用错的手拿义子 你就完蛋了
You are the worst person in the whole world,
你是全世界最差劲的人
committed the greatest sin.
犯下最大的罪孽
All such small, stupid ideas come out of a very depraved ego.
所有这种细微愚蠢的想法都是 来自堕落的自我
Ego is so depraved
自我是那么堕落
when you start thinking no end of yourself -
当你只想着自己
that “I'm everything
我是一切
and I know everything,”
我知道一切
and “this custom is the best,” or “that carpet is the best.” “I, I,
和 这个习俗是最好的 或 地毯是最好的 我 我
I don’t like.” Well, who are you?
我不喜欢 好吧 你是谁
Who asked you to like it or not to like it?
谁叫你喜欢它 或不喜欢它
“I don’t like this, I don’t like that.”
我不喜欢这个 我不喜欢那
On the other side, the egoists always becomes slaves also.
另一方面 自我中心的人常常变成奴隶
I must say that after going through the countries
我是在查看过很多
which are following certain norms,
遵守某种社会准则的国家 才必须这样说
which are dictations of the ego.
这些制约只是自我的默写
Like an artist, now for example.
就以艺术家为例
An artist produces something for his joy,
艺术家为个人的喜乐而创作
but he must be criticized by everyone.
但他必定受到每个人的批评
The criticism should be,
批评应该是这样的
“I don’t like this, this color is no good, that is not.”
我不喜欢这个 这种颜色不好 这个不好
And you have professionals who do this.
你们就是有这种职业批评家
They don’t know how to even draw one pencil line properly
但他们却连用铅笔 好好的画一条直线也不懂
leave alone painting anything,
更不用说画点什么
but immediately they’ll say, “I think this, this is …you see.”‘
他们立即会说 我认为这是 这是 你看
They have made books out of it,
他们在这种情况下出版书籍
theses and theories.
提出这些理论
I mean,
我是说
art has something to do with your heart and not with your brain.
艺术是用心创造 不是用脑袋
That’s how you have killed so many artists.
这就是为何你们握杀了很多艺术家
And everybody who is painting has to think
每一个绘画的人都要想
what people will say about this.
什么人会说我的作品
But as a result of that, something absolutely absurd,
因此 一些绝对荒唐粗浅的
gross,
作品滋长
without any subtle expression, is today appreciated.
这些作品没有表达任何精微 却能在今天获得赏识
This is because of our ego
这是因为我们的自我
which has suppressed every proper, spontaneous,
我们正常的 自然而然的
living growth of our thought, of our art and of our life.
活生生的思绪压制了 亦压制了我们的艺术和生命
I think it’s worse than all the contamination we talk about
我想这比我们谈及的污染和
or ecological problems.
生态问题更差劲
It’s the human mind which has produced these
是人类的头脑产生
suffocating areas where nobody can express anything,
这个令人窒息的空间 因此没有人能表达什么
and the one who has a greater ego dominates.
自我最大的人控制一切
“This book has been written by such-and-such person.”
这本书是某某人写的
You meet that person, you feel like jumping in the sea.
你与这个人见面 你感到像跳进海洋里
So everything written is not a bible,
一切写下来的都不是圣经
and those mostly who write are people
写书的人大多是
whom you should never meet without a bargepole.
若你没有撑篙 就不应与他见面的人
So anything that is expressed, you see, say in a dress or
所以任何要表达的 就如衣服
in relationship with your children,
或与你的孩子的关系
in relationship with your teacher, in relationship with anyone,
与你老师的关系 与任何人的关系
has to be so and so and so.
必须要像这样
You must say “thank you” many a times;
你必须说 谢谢 很多次
you must say “sorry” many a times.
也必须说 对不起 很多次
So we are so much curbed into artificial expressions
我们被困在虚假的措辞表情里
that I think after some time there will be no art produced.
我想一段时间后 再没有艺术创作
There’s no exuberance.
没有生气勃勃的活动
They cannot, they're afraid.
他们没法创作 他们害怕
I don’t know if you have noticed this or not,
我不知道你有没有注意到这种情况
but those who go to see any museum, or go to see any exhibition,
任何到博物馆的人 或去看展览的人
anything, think, all of them, to be great,
我想他们全都有了不起
some divine personalities that they can judge everyone.
上天的个性去评价每一个人
Through the Agnya that we judge,
我们是透过额轮评价人
that is what Hanumana wanted to eat once for all.
这是哈奴曼一次过想吃掉的
There’s the movement of the Agnya which goes right and left, you see,
额轮往右又往左移动
which makes us
令我们表达那个所谓
express our so-called, nonsensical personality of a ego.
荒唐个性的自我 他就是想控制自我
It’s the one that He tried to control and eat it off.
把自我吃掉 就如我吃掉恶魔
As I eat bhoots, perhaps He was eating this sun.
或许祂也吃掉了太阳
But for an angel it is important to know that
对天使而言 要知道你内在没有
there is no ego within you.
自我是很重要的
There are some Sahaja yogis
有些霎哈嘉瑜伽士说
who say, “Mother, I didn’t want to do too much of
母亲 我不想做太多霎哈嘉瑜伽的工作
Sahaja Yoga work because my ego will come up.”
因为我不想自我出现
Many. “I don’t want my ego to express it.”
很多这样的霎哈嘉瑜伽士 我不想自我显现出来
But why do you want your ego to be destroyed, for what?
为何你想摧毁自我 为什么
For Sahaja Yoga work isn’t it?
为了能做霎哈嘉瑜伽的工作 对吗
What a vicious circle it is that we say that we want to
这是何等的邪恶循环
keep ourselves in the background because our ego should not develop.
我们说我们想保持在背后 因此自我不能发展
You are just thinking about yourself.
你只想着自己
What about Sahaja Yoga?
霎哈嘉瑜伽又如何
So nowadays the trend is, “Oh, better be on the safe side.”
现在的趋势是 噢 最好处于安全的位置
Because they have seen some people who were very egoistical,
因为他们见过一些很自我中心的人
who were very dashing about Sahaja Yoga,
这些人对霎哈嘉瑜伽很有冲劲
So another trend has started, I feel, in Sahaja Yoga that
所以另一趋势已经开展 我感到 在霎哈嘉瑜伽
“Better be on the safe side,” you see.
最好站在安全位置  你看
Between these two, Sahaja Yoga will be lost.
在这两者之间 霎哈嘉瑜伽会迷失
So if you know you are angels, you'll have no ego.
若你知道自己是天使 就不会有自我
Anybody who knows that it’s his nature to do something.
任何人知道这是他的本质做一点事
Like today My husband was praising Me saying that
就像今天 我丈夫赞赏我 说
“It is You Who has done it.” I said, “Not Me. It’s not Me.”
是你做这件事 我说 不是我 不是我
He said, “How do You say it is not You?”
他说 你怎么说不是你
“Because,” I said, “It is innately built in them.
我说 因为这是他们天生内在已经建构好
A seed, if it is planted in the Mother Earth, then it sprouts.
一颗种子 若把它播放在大地之母 它自会发芽生长
In the same way, they have innately built within them
同样 他们内在已经天生建构好灵量
their Kundalinis It sprouts.
它发芽
So how is it I have done?”
所以怎会是我做的
“But,” he said. “But the Mother Earth has done it.”
他说 大地之母也要让它发芽
I said, “No,
我说 不是
it's the quality in Mother Earth which is built in, has done it.”
是大地之母已经建构好的品质 种子必须发芽
So he said, “Then who has done all this?”
他因此说 那么是谁做这些工作
So I said, “It's done by Adi Shakti, agreed.
我答 是太初之母 同意吧
But, Sahaja Yoga is not done by Adi Shakti.
霎哈嘉瑜伽不是太初之母创造的
She has created these powers in everyone which works out,
她已经在每一个人身上创造了 能成就事情的力量
but Sahaja Yoga is not.
不是霎哈嘉瑜伽
Sahaja Yoga works through the innate qualities
霎哈嘉瑜伽透过在大地之母的天生品质
that are in the Mother Earth and that are in the seed.
以及在种子内的品质成就事情
So I’m here as... not as Adi Shakti.
我来这里 不是以太初之母的身分
I’m here as their Mother, as their Holy Mother,
而是以母亲的身分 以他们神圣的母亲来
and as Holy Mother I’ve guided them.”
作为神圣的母亲 我指引他们
You can say I’m like the Mother Earth  who sprouts the seeds.
你可以说 我像大地之母 令种子发芽
So then another detachment can come in, into you,
因此另一种不执着临到你们身上
that these are your powers within you which have been
这是你内在的力量
just enlightened by your innate nature of Kundalini.
它开悟了你灵量的天生本质
And that you are empowered, yourself.
你是自己授权自己
And all this power that is within you
所有力量都是在你内里
is only told by Me that it is within you. You see for yourself.
我只是告诉你 你内在已经拥有这些力量 你自己看看
Only like a mirror I’m telling you,
我告诉你 就像照镜
“You are this, see for yourself.”
你是这样 你自己看看
So how can I take any credit for it?
因此 又怎能归功于我呢
So you can even have detachment to understand that
所以你甚至能不执着的去明白
the powers that we have is for Sahaja Yoga.
我们拥有的力量是为霎哈嘉瑜伽而设
As Mother has powers to work for Sahaja Yoga,
就如母亲有力量为霎哈嘉瑜伽工作
we too have powers to work for Sahaja Yoga.
我们也有力量为霎哈嘉瑜伽工作
And as She works, we also have to work.
就如她工作 我们也要工作
But there is attachment like this,
但有这样的执着
“Mother is doing everything, what can we do?”
母亲在做一切 我们能做什么
No! You have to do it.
不 你要去做
This is a very important detachment, which I’m trying to say
我想说 这是很重要的不执着
that you have to do this yourself.
你要为自己而做
It’s not that Mother will do.
不是母亲要做
“After all, Mother is doing everything.”
不管如何 母亲在做一切
It's correct, that is correct in a way,
对 某程度这是对的
but you are the instrument.
但你是工具
Electricity is doing everything here but this instrument has to work.
在这里 电力在做一切 但这个工具也必须运作
So the source may be there but
源头或许在这里
the instrument is the one which delivers the goods.
但运送货物则要用工具
And like Hanumana, you are the instrument
就如哈奴曼 你是工具
and you have to work, you have to do the job.
你要工作 你要做这任务
It’s in a very dynamic we should achieve.
这是我们要完成事情很有活力的方式
Another great quality of Hanumana was that
哈奴曼另一个了不起的品质是
He was very alert
他很有警觉性
and that He was beyond time.
他超越时间
When you eat off the sun, where is the time?
当你吃掉太阳 时间在哪里
Because of that, everything He did very fast.
因此 他做的一切都很快速
For example, now we are preparing say
例如 我们在写一本
a book of Sahaja Yoga.
霎哈嘉瑜伽的书籍
For the last sixteen years it’s going on.
在过去十六年都在写
“It’s working out, Mother, working out.”
母亲 这能做到 能做到
Then we are trying to make some arrangements about having
我们尝试作出安排
the recording of the sick people and being cured with Sahaja Yoga.
把用霎哈嘉瑜伽治好的病人记录下来
“That’s happening, very good, happening, happening.”
这样在发生 很好 在发生 在发生
Then we are going to go to Russia to spread Sahaja Yoga.
我们要到俄罗斯传播霎哈嘉瑜伽
“Ah, working out.”
啊 在成就
All the devils have reached there, but the angels are still working it out,
所有恶魔都到达那里 天使仍在成就它
very patient, very patient angels.
很有耐性 很有耐性的天使
So one of the qualities of Shri Hanumana was that
哈奴曼其中一个品质是
He was a fast person.
他很快速
He would do the work before anybody could do it.
他会在别人做这份工作前就把工作完成
He was out beat.
他抢先一步
It’s all right to fight in Trafalgar and win and defeat Napolean,
在特拉法加(Trafalgar) 作战 要战胜 要打败拿破仑没问题
but in the field of dharma and the field of Sahaja Yoga,
但在正法的领域 在霎哈嘉瑜伽的领域
I find people don’t understand the importance of time.
我发觉人们不明白时间的重要
We are delayed masters, and dilatory habits we have.
我们都是迟到大师 都有拖延的习惯
“All right, I’ll telephone. I’ll find out and it will happen.”
好吧 我会打电话 我们会找出来 它会发生
This is one of the greatest defects
这是我们最大的缺点
we have which we have to learn from Hanumana,
因此 我们要向哈奴曼学习
that Rama wanted to send word,
罗摩想下命令
so He sent His ring with Hanumana.
祂命令哈奴曼带着祂的戒指去办这件事
Rama could not do that fast,
罗摩没法做得那么快
so Hanumana went and did it.
所以哈奴曼走去把工作办好
Then Rama wanted to have this sanjivani, this kind of a herb.
罗摩想要sanjivani 一种草药
So He sent Him to get from particular mountain.
祂派哈奴曼到一个特定的山脉去拿
He said, "Now why to waste time finding it out?
哈奴曼说 为何要浪费时间找草药
Better take the whole thing."
不如整座山拿来
So He carried the whole mountain there.
他把整座山拿来
“Better do it quickly, immediately, this is the time to do it.”
最好是快速地 马上去办 现在就是要把事情办妥的时间
But, “Next year we’ll see. Mother, You know, after Ganapatipule,
可是 母亲 明年我们会看看 你也知道 在格纳帕蕾普蕾之后
we can consider.
我们才会考虑
We’ll have discussions,
我们要商量一下
and then we’ll have arguments," and this and that.
接着 我们会有争论 这样那样
This is one thing about His character one has to know,
我们对哈奴曼的个性要知道的一件事情
that today, when we are worshipping Hanumana,
就是今天当我们敬拜他
we should have that quick-wittedness within us.
我们要有这种快速的脑筋
It is to be done now.
要现在就做
We cannot postpone it anymore.
不能再拖延
Already we are very much delayed.
我们已经很迟了
I saw the girls who were wearing frocks,
我看到女孩子穿长裙
small little things have grown into big girls now, about to be married.
小家伙现在长成大女孩 快要结婚
So I think all My life I'll be marrying only Sahaja Yogis.
所以我想 我的一生只会嫁给霎哈嘉瑜伽士
To see the results you have to become quick people.
要看到成效 你就要快速
Not to linger and be satisfied with other things.
不要徘徊拖延 亦不要只满足于其他事物
But positive things, what are we doing?
要正面 我们在做什么
For example, it’s nice, children have grown up,
例如 这很好 孩子已经长大成人
they had such a nice drama,
他们有这样美好的戏剧
play, all that I enjoyed very much.
表演 我全都很享受
It was very good for everybody’s enjoyment,
对每个人这也是很好的娱乐
but job is there, we have to do. We have to do the job.
但仍有工作 我们都要去做 去做这些工作
So attention should be on the job,
注意力要放在工作上
and that’s what, what are we doing about it?
就工作而言 我们做了些什么
I was happy that a suggestion has come from America about
我很高兴 有个来自美国的建议
making a video film and things like that.
是关于电影制作 和类似的事情
And then there are obstructions:
接着有些障碍
“How are we going to get money, what is going to happen?”
我们怎样拿到资金 什么要发生
You just start it, you’ll get it.
你只要开展工作 就会拿到钱
You have powers.
你拥有力量
Everything will be synchronized properly, you just start doing it.
一切都会恰当的同步发生 你只要开始做就行
But if you behave like human beings - first think
但若你像人类般行事  先想想
then plan it out, and then cancel it -
再计划 接着取消计划
it’s not going to work out.
这将不会有任何成就
Though Hanumana is running on the Pingala Nadi all the time,
虽然哈奴曼每时每刻都在右脉奔跑
what He does is to spoil our plans
他做的事情却是令我们的计划泡汤
because, instead of Him, we run on the Pingala.
因为我们取代他在右脉奔跑
So He says, “All right, you running it? I’ll put you right!”
好吧 你在奔跑 我会纠正你
So He sidetracks all our plans all the time.
所以他常常转移我们的计划
That’s how all our planning fails.
就这样我们所有的计划都失败告终
We are particular about timing, about things of no importance,
我们在意时间 在意不重要的事情
but we are not particular about timings of our progress in Sahaja Yoga.
但却不在意掌握我们在霎哈嘉瑜伽的进度
We must have targets, we must have fixed times,
我们必须有目标 有固定的时间
“All right, by this time we have to achieve,”
好吧 这个时间我们要达成这个进度
but do it little faster is better.
快一点更好
All other things can be managed, but this is your job,
其他事情可以代你处理 但这是你的工作
nobody’s going to do it.
没有人会代你去做
Nobody’s going to do it, it’s your job.
这是你的工作
I mean you are not going to run the train,
我是说你不用追火车
you are not going to run aeroplanes
不用追飞机
and you don’t have to run any administration and this stupid politics,
不用追逐任何管理 不用追逐这种愚蠢的政治
but you have to do Sahaja Yoga.
但你要做霎哈嘉瑜伽的工作
You have to spread it; you have to bring it
要传扬霎哈嘉瑜伽 要把霎哈嘉瑜伽带到
to a level where people can see it.
让人们能看到的层次
Now eighteen years have passed, this is the nineteenth year.
现在 十八年已经过去 今年是第十九年
I must say you have to venture.
我必须说 你要历险
You have to venture without any fear, collectively and individually,
无畏无惧 集体地 个别地去历险
forgetting as to what will happen.
忘记什么会发生
I mean you won’t go to jails,
我是说你不会进监狱
you will not be crucified, be sure on that.
不会被钉上十字架 这是肯定的
I mean if you lose your job, you can get another,
我是说即使你失去工作 也能找到另一份工作
and if you don’t get a job, you can get a dole all right.
若你找不到工作 可以拿失业救济金
So you don’t have to worry about all
所以不用担心这些人类通常
useless things which human beings sit down and worry;
坐下来就担心的无用事情
but despite that they achieve work,
虽然如此 他们完成工作
they do their jobs,
做他们的工作
and how much they're wedded to it I’m surprised.
我很惊讶是他们怎样深陷于工作的罗网里
I’ve seen it in My family
我在我的家庭见过
how much they're wedded. They have to do this work,
他们怎样陷进工作的罗网中 他们要做这份工作
they have to get up in the morning, do this, do that.
他们要早上起床 做这事情做那事情
But you are not aware that you are angels and this is your work.
你没有意识到 你既是天使 这亦是你的工作
You have to do this and nothing else is important.
你必须做这份工作 没有什么比它更重要
I hope by today’s puja, that enthusiasm,
我希望借着今天的崇拜 借着这份热诚
that venturesome nature
这份好冒险的本质
will vibrate your Pingala,
让你的右脉充满生命能量
and without feeling any ego about it,
让你没有任何自我的感觉
in the most humble manner as Hanumana was,
只感到如哈奴曼那么谦卑
you will do the jobs.
你会做这份工作
Hanumana, imagine, He was given a beautiful necklace of gold
哈奴曼 试想像 有人给祂一条漂亮的金项链
with big, big balls for Him to wear by Sita.
项链上有很大很大的球 要他戴上 悉旦给祂的
And He opened all of them one by one.
他把球一个一个的打开
He said, “There is no Rama in this, what will I do with this gold?”
说 罗摩不在球内 我要这些金有什么用
So She said, “Where is Rama?”
她问 罗摩在哪里
He opened His heart and showed it, “See, Rama is here.”
他打开心 让她看 看 罗摩就在这里
If Rama is there you cannot have ego.
若罗摩在哪里 我们就不能有自我
So, so much of dynamism and so much of humility –
那么有活力 那么谦虚
what a combination it was!
这是怎样的结合
And that’s what you have to just manifest.
你就是要彰显这些品质
The more you’ll work, the more you’ll assert yourself,
你越工作 越能坚持自己
you will find that humility is the only thing that helps.
你会发现只有谦虚能帮上忙
Obedience is the only thing that helps  to carry out your work
唯一能帮你执行工作的是服从
and you’ll become humbler and humbler.
你会变得越来越谦虚
But if you think, "Oh I am doing this," then finished.
但若你想 噢 是我在做 那就完蛋了
But if you know that it’s done by the Divine,
若你知道这是上天做的
“Paramchaitanya is doing everything, I am just an instrument,”
Paramchaitanya(上天无所不在的生命能量) 成就万事万物 我只是件工具
the humility will be there and you will be an effective instrument.
谦虚油然而生 你会是很有效率的工具
I hope in this country today,
今天在这个国家
it was very necessary and it was so timely.
很需要也合时机
It was all organized by angels that we should have this puja here.
全都是天使统筹 我们要在这里做崇拜
But it’s good for all of you.
这对你们全部人都是好事
You have to really go and see the media people,
你们真的要探访这些传媒人
go and see these ministers, go and see, say, Prince of Wales.
这些部长 探访他们 例如韦尔斯王子
Go and see another person, meet them, make committees,
去探访一些人 与他们见面 成立委员会
see what you can do.
看看你能做什么
Put your mind to it, "What are we to do?"
把心思放在这些事情上 我们能做什么
But here only, “My mother is sick, my child is sick,
但这里的人却 我母亲病了 我孩子病了
my this thing is sick, my friend is sick my …,” still going on with it.
我这些事情出问题 我朋友病了 仍然有这些问题
If you start doing God’s work, your worries are taken over.
若你开始做神的工作 你的担忧会被接管
You don’t have to worry about anything, just taken over.
你不用担忧什么  担忧都被接管
But it’s not self-propagation, it’s not!
这不是自我宣传 不是
It’s the propagation of the collective.
是宣传集体
I hope today you have understood the subtle side of your being
我希望今天你们都已经明白 你存在体精微的一面
which is there, which is exhibiting, which I can see clearly,
它就在这里 在展现 我能清楚的看到它
and that you will, all of you will
你们全部人都会在入静中
in your meditation become aware of what you have within yourself.
你意识到你内在拥有什么
That’s the greatest thing
这是你能取悦上天
that will please the Divine, and Divine will look after you fully
最了不起的东西 你亦会得到上天的照顾
with the same confidence as the angels.
如天使哈奴曼一样
Like Hanumana you have to go further and work it out.
拥有同样的信心 你要再进一步 把它成就
May God bless you all.
愿神祝福你们
I have to say about the ego part is this,
我要说到自我
which is really the problem in the West, why people have so much ego
这真的是西方国家的问题 为何他们有
than Indian people have.
比印度人更大的自我
One of the things is that
其一是右边
the right side, as I've told you many-a-times, is like an accelerator.
就如我多次告诉你们 像加速器
The left side is like the brake.
左边像煞车器
So if the Mooladhara is not in control, if the brake is not all right,
若根轮不受控制 若煞车器不妥当
naturally that accelerator cannot be controlled.
加速器自然不受控制
So basically our Mooladhara should be brought round
所以基本上我们的根轮要恢复过来
and must be put right.
要得到纠正
You should work very hard to do that. If your brake is established,
为此你要很努力工作 若你建立好煞车器
then whatever work you do for Sahaja Yoga,
不管你为霎哈嘉瑜伽做什么工作
you'll not get into ego practices
都不会有自我
and ego cannot anymore control you.
自我不能再控制你
So that is very important, specially in the West where
这是很重要 特别是西方
it’s being really, dangerously destroyed, the idea of auspiciousness
他们很危险的摧毁吉祥和
and of holiness.
神圣的观念
So that is the power of any angel
因此任何天使的力量必须
and that has to be fully established within us,
在我们内在完全建立
and then on that power will work out,
那么这个力量就能成就事情
which gives you discretion, which gives you egolessness.
给你辨别能力 令你毫无自我
I hope today both these things will work out within us in such a manner
我希望今天两者都能在你内在建立
that we really become absolutely self-confident,
让你真的变成完全自信的
realized souls whom I call as angels of modern times.
有自觉的灵 我称这些灵为现代的天使